Nathaniel Ehrlich

<u>nwehrlich@gmail.com</u> | 720.697.9293 | Denver, CO 80220 <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nwehrlich</u> | <u>https://github.com/TechnoPrep</u> | <u>https://www.nwehrlich.com/</u>

Summary

Web Developer with a background in Customer Service. Constant self-reflection to see what there is to learn from a situation, and how this can help the development of the best version of myself. Recognized as proactive, resourceful, and persistent problem-solver. Excellent communicator with effective client relationship-building skills. Graduate of Web Development Bootcamp through the University Of Denver.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript, ReactJS, PHP, Bootstrap, AJAX, Bulma, FontAwesome, Handlebars. Backend: GraphQL, MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, Express, Node, REST API's.

Projects

Total Ticket | http://total-ticket.com/ Express / Node Expert | Dataflow Doctor | API Researcher | Database Administrator

- Event Ticket Price Comparison app
- This application creates a centralized platform to connect event-goers to their favorite performers and venues, allowing them to find the best ticket, for the best price across multiple Ticket Purchasing sites.
- JavaScript, GraphQL, MongoDB, NodeJS, Heroku, JSON Web Token, Apollo, React, Session Management

Remindr | https://remindr-notification.herokuapp.com/ Project Manager | Express / Node Expert | Database Administrator

- Email / SMS (In Development) notification app
- This application allows you to set notification reminders from the Dashboard for follow-up emails. Roled involved Lead Developer of the Project, delegating responsibilities to other members and holding Stand-Ups to resolve blockers. Created the API management between front-end and back-end Database communication.
- JavaScript, JQuery, Sequelize, NodeJS, Heroku, JawsDB MySQL, Session Management

Relevant Work Experience

Junior Achievement

Apr. 2021 – Current

Application Administrator Denver, CO

- Handled 8 different applications, managing their Databases and App Services.
- Responsible for resolving end-user application issues across 103 Junior Achievement Areas.
- Created internal documentation for the Infrastructure Team to resolve Database Issues.
- Managing bug triaging and proposing solutions to our 3rd Party Development Teams.

SchoolMessenger

Jun. 2016 - Apr. 2021

Customer Solution Expert

Joplin, MO

- Built custom PHP scripts for user data from multiple Student Information System (SIS) to our application
- Developed documentation for SIS integration, and Custom Mobile App deployment processes
- Liaison between the Support and Development Team, Reporting Outages and working with internal teams to notify customers of issues and to ensure they were resolved in a timely fashion.
- Responsible for the largest School District in the CA that serves 247,000 students yearly as the primary contact.

Additional Work Experience

EGS Solutions

Customer Care Specialist

Joplin, MO

- Maintained highest consistent CSAT score for 2 consecutive years.
- Assisted end-users with Intuit Tax Software, Desktop, and Online Application.
- Lead training classes with other facilitators during peak season.
- Worked directly with Intuit Management to help resolve bottlenecks during peak season.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Denver, Denver, CO Dec 2021

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.